directlink.com 2015-06-07

# Posten’s privacy policy

## Handling personal data

Posten AB (“Posten”) takes visitor privacy to this website seriously. We take responsibility for ensuring that any personal data processed by Posten is used only for the intended purpose, and that it is protected from unauthorized use and access. Our goal is that you feel confident that your personal privacy is respected and that your personal data is treated with discretion.

The personal data you provide will be used to provide you with products, information and services you have requested, as well as for sales, development and monitoring. Personal data may also be used for marketing purposes, unless you submit a written request to not receive direct marketing. We may give your personal data to other companies in the PostNord Group or to the PostNord Group’s data processor. Beyond that, we will not share your personal data with a third party without your consent.

This privacy policy is general to Posten’s website. If further privacy policies are posted on linked sites operated by other legal entities within the PostNord Group, these will take precedence.

.

## IP address registration

When you visit posten.se, your IP address is automatically registered to measure the frequency of visits.

## Identification when collecting parcels/mailings

When collecting a parcel or mailing from one of Posten’s agents, i.e. a Posten partner outlet or Business Service Center, you must bring some form of identification. Posten checks identification to make sure no unauthorized party collects the parcel or mailing. We then register or scan the identity document number and save it with the identity number on the parcel/shipment (the parcel ID number) for 12 months. The information is used if you or the sender need to submit a complaint; see “Complaints” below.

## Complaints

For example, if you submit a complaint regarding a parcel that did not arrive, we register the sender, the recipient, the day the parcel was given to Posten, the contents of the parcel and any other information that may help us track the parcel or its contents if the parcel was damaged. Even with other types of complaints, the information you submit will be registered with Posten and used to handle your case.

## Confidentiality within Posten

Posten’s confidentiality policy applies to shipment items under the Postal Services Act, but other information about Posten’s customers is also treated as confidential. Address information in the mail carrier’s database may be given to authorities in some cases, as required by law or other regulation.

## Registration of personal identity number

Certain services require a secure form of identification; therefore we need to register and process your personal identity number. If you are a sole proprietor and Posten customer, your personal identity number is registered because it is your corporate registration number. 

## Storage of personal d

## ata

If you have an account at posten.se, your personal data will be stored in posten.se’s customer database for 3 years from the time you last logged in. You can always close your posten.se account by logging in to posten.se or contacting customer service.

## Personal data controller

Posten AB is responsible for the handling of personal data that takes place on this website, under the privacy protection legislation in the Swedish Personal Data Act (1998:204). Other legal entities in the PostNord Group that provide services or functions on this website are, where applicable, separately responsible for the handling of personal data in accordance with the terms of the relevant service/function. 

## Database excerpts and corrections

Once per calendar year, you are entitled to receive free information about the personal data Posten keeps on file about you. You are also entitled to request corrections to incorrect or misleading personal data. Requests for corrections or for a database excerpt should be submitted in writing to the following address. 

Posten AB  
Personuppgiftsombudet  
105 00 STOCKHOLM

## Related content
